# Elias Woldeselassie

Motivated and Dynamic Web Developer / Programmer

#### **Professional Summary**

I am a web developer with 4+ years of experience in developing and maintaining web applications. I have a strong background in React.js, Node.js, Python and Django framework. I am also experienced in working with databases such as MSSQL, MySQL and MongoDB. I have a passion for creating user-friendly and visually appealing websites and applications. I am also experienced in working with frameworks such as Bootstrap and Material UI.

## **Professional Experience**

## Flex Logistic and Transportation | Seattle

## Frontend Engineer June 2019 - Current

- Collaborated with other developers to ensure the quality of the codebase
- Implemented new features and bug fixes to improve the user experience
- Optimized the performance of the web applications by utilizing React
- Performed comprehensive unit testing on complex code.
- Responsible for creating an efficient design and developing user interaction screens using react and react-bootstrap.
- Designed frontend within object-oriented JavaScript libraries
- Working on creating a responsive website for smart devices using responsive design and media queries.

#### Backend developer January 2018 - May 2019

- Designed and developed the server module and resolved issues and was responsible for its enhancements.
- Architected and developed Python & Django for the backend development.
- Worked on Diango ORM module for signing complex queries.
- Developed views and templates with Django view controller and template to create a user-friendly website interface.
- Worked on Jira for managing the tasks and improving performance.

### **Freelance | Various Clients**

#### **MERN Stack Developer** February 2017 - December 2017

- Developed and maintained web applications using the MERN stack and related technologies for a variety of clients
- Worked closely with clients to understand their needs and deliver highquality solutions on tight deadlines
- Utilized agile development methodologies and strong communication skills to successfully deliver projects on time and on budget

Seattle, WA 98108 +1 206-715-1908

ewoldese2000@gmail.com

https://elias-wold.netlify.app/

https://github.com/Melijah5

www.linkedin.com/in/eliaswoldeselassie

#### Skills

**Languages** - JavaScript, MySql Query, Python, MSSQL Query, Shell scripting, Django ORM

Web Technology - HTML5, CSS3, React JS, jQuery, Redux, Node.js, Webpack, Django, React-Router, bootstrap

**Version Control**: Git, GitHub, bit Bucket

**Databases** - MySQL, MongoDB, MSSQL

**Operating System**: windows, Ubuntu , linux and MAC

**Networking:** TCP/IP config

**Deployment Tools**: AWS EC2 , Heroku, Docker, Firestore

#### **Education & Award**

#### **Adama University**

- BSc Information Science

#### **Coding Dojo**

- Full stack development

#### Evagadi Tech

- Full stack development **Microsoft** 

 Certified in Querying Microsoft SQL Serve